Florence Dela Cruz, there's a letter for you.
Is that the result
of your college admission test?
- I got accepted!
- What?
You got accepted!
- Yes!
- My daughter got accepted!
This is for Florence.
- For Florence.
- For Florence!
And this is for all of us.
- Yes, for all of us.
- Yes, for all of us!
Federico?
What happened?
We still have money left.
I also called your grandfather.
He said he'll help us out.
We can do this, Mother.
We will fight, and we will win.
I have a side hustle for you.
Side hustle?
All you have to do is cook delicious food.
Now, cook me your best recipe.
Prove to me that you can cook
for the grandchildren of Don Ferell.
This is very good.
It means you're hired, Ms. Florence.
Really?
Thank you, Sir!
And I think it's better
if she meets the kids,
because after all,
she'll be cooking for them.
I'm sure that all your grandchildren
are so cute.
You be the judge.
Good thing that you're early.
You can start doing lunch
for Don Ferell's grandsons.
As you already know,
they are very picky eaters.
That's why you have to ask them
what they want to eat
before you start cooking in the kitchen.
You will receive half of your salary
every 15th,
and, of course,
the other half is every end of the month.
You will be provided for
with everything that you need,
from soap, toothpaste, and shampoo,
and among other thing else,
like SSS, Philhealth, and Pag-Ibig.
You only need to focus on one thing,
and one thing alone.
Your job. And that is, to cook.
And you'll be in charge in securing
if you have enough kitchen supplies
from meats,
eggs, canned goods, seasoning, milk,
and of course, included also are vegetables
and fruits, okay?
Now, you have to be aware of what's lacking
and what is needed to be changed.
If you're not sure
if something is still fresh,
then throw it away and don't regret it.
What?
But that's a pity,
a lot of people are hungry nowadays.
So?
The world can starve for all I care,
but what's important is all the grandsons
of Don Ferell will eat fresh food.
That's why your kitchen must provide
whatever they ask for.
Also, there are rules.
They eat in their respective rooms
according to their own schedule
and when they want to eat.
That's why you have to be available for them
anytime they need you to serve them.
Now, the kitchen will be yours
and yours alone, Ms. Florence.
All the responsibilities rest on you,
so everybody in this household will eat,
understood?
I'm very understanding, Ms. Serafica, so yes.
I understood everything.
Very good.
Follow me.
Walk this way.
Hurry.
Everyone, this is Florence.
Hi, Florence.
I'm Patotina, maid number 2.
Good luck.
Hi. My name is James.
Driver number 2. Good luck.
Iking, Florence... Iking.
Wait, aren't you the mailman?
No, that's just my part-time job.
But this is my main job, I'm gardener 1.
And I'm sure you know Dencio.
Well, I will leave you.
Follow me.
Walk this way.
She said to follow her.
This will be your room.
And it will be your own personal space.
Once you're done with all your work,
you can retire here
and no one will bother you.
As you can see,
I have provided you with your uniforms.
We must always look professional.
You will have access to wi-fi,
and the password is
"Ferell brothers are super hot and awesome",
with the capital letter F,
no space in between.
Don't bother to ask,
the boys set that password.
But if you'll ask me,
it will be Capital Letter I,
small letters l, u, s, uppercase G-M-A,
SHARPSEVEN number 1.
No space in between.
Oh, by the way, Ms. Florence,
I must warn you.
Don't thinks that just because
you're accepted, you're already secured.
You can only make a mistake once
and after that,
I will personally drag you out of here.
I will not tolerate incompetence.
So, settle down
and proceed to meet the boys in the game room
and ask them what they want to eat,
and then start preparing their meals.
- Clear?
- Yes.
Okay.
Good luck.
Wow.
This room is so grand.
This is bigger than our house.
Cabinets, kitchen, but here we go.
Speaking of the kitchen,
are you ready, Florence,
because if you're ready,
give me an F, give me an L,
give me an O, R, E, N, C, E!
I'm Florence Dela Cruz and I'm ready to cook!
I can cook sinigang, pinakbet, adobo, tinola,
nilaga, everything, Florence can do that.
So for the heart, for you, dear hearts,
for Mother and Father, let's go!
Start! Let's go, Florence.
Hi, Sir Aldus.
What would you like to have for lunch today?
I want sushi.
But please make sure you slice it
thinly and properly.
The same way how Chef Jiro does it.
Do you know him?
You better watch him,
so you'd learn how to make sushi properly.
Make sure the tuna is fresh.
And freshly cut and I don't want it frozen.
It should be as fresh as
the tunas in the Tsukiji market,
something that would make me
feel that I'm in Japan.
Get it?
Move over.
What are you waiting for?
Sushi, coming up.
Hello, Sir Troy,
what do you want for lunch today?
Sir Troy, what would you like for lunch?
Can't you see I'm playing?
Sir Troy, I still need
to buy the ingredients.
Destroy.
It's your fault.
I want a paella valenciana.
Okay.
But please, don't put chorizo.
No chorizo.
Is that all?
All right.
But I also want something
like paella verduras,
the one with red bell pepper,
zucchini, and tomatoes.
Yeah.
Is that it?
But also make it like paella negra,
and put some squid ink on it.
Is that it?
But not too much.
It's not appetizing anymore if it's too dark.
Not too dark.
Is that all?
Yeah.
Are you sure?
Yeah?
Sir Tristan, what's your order?
Sir?
What's with you? I'm lifting weights.
I'm sorry.
I want an apple pie.
Apple pie...
No, no, lemon pie...
- Lemon pie.
- No, I want mango pie...
But I hope there's a layer of sugary crust,
but it shouldn't be too crusty.
Crusty, not crunchy.
I don't want the sound of crunch
when I eat it.
And please, I don't want just any mangoes.
I want Guimaras mangoes.
The sweetest and the best mangoes
in the world.
Mango pie, Sir, with Guimaras mangoes?
Sure.
- What's that?
- Sushi.
What's this?
I said I want to dream of sushi,
but with what you did,
it's like I'll have a nightmare.
I'm not going to eat that.
That's an insult to Japanese culture,
that's an insult to human civilization.
Take that out in front of me.
Out!
- What's that?
- Paella negra.
Even a stray dog who hasn't eaten for months
won't eat that.
And now you're asking me to eat it?
Are you crazy?
Or are you planning on making me sick?
Nice one.
Mango pie, Sir.
I'm sorry I wasn't able
to find Guimaras mangoes.
What do you mean you can't find
Guimaras mangoes here in Levante?
So you made a mango pie
where mangoes were harvested
from just anywhere?
That is not okay.
There's no mango
sweeter than Guimaras mangoes.
And I was very clear that
what I want is Guimaras mango!
Do you think I'll eat that
when you settled for less?
Are you okay?
Don't be shy.
A philosopher once said,
"crying makes us human".
Philosopher?
Which philosopher?
Me.
So, you're the philosopher among them.
I'm just trying to make you laugh.
Thank you.
I guess you're aware that
they're just playing with you.
I know that.
I can feel that they're challenging me.
But what can I do when I'm really your cook?
I was clearly instructed
that you, guys, are my priority.
So, whatever you want to eat,
no matter how difficult it is to cook,
I need to find a way.
I'm sorry.
You keep saying sorry
when there's nothing to be sorry about.
You only asked me to cook a scrambled egg.
To be fair, the scrambled eggs were perfect.
Really?
It looks like you're just saying it
to make me feel better.
Well, yes, I'm trying to cheer you up,
but it doesn't change the fact
that my scrambled eggs were delicious.
Tomorrow, I want it sunny side up.
So you're fond of eggs.
Just take it easy,
it might turn you into a chicken.
Good one.
Thank you.
I needed a pep talk from
the philosopher of the Ferells.
But don't worry,
tomorrow, I'll be okay again.
I, out of all people, won't give up.
You're brave.
Did you see her earlier?
She was so pitiful, Bro.
I think she's not the brightest.
Imagine, she looked for Guimaras mangoes
for my mango pie here in Levante.
I saw her when I passed by the kitchen,
she was basically watching UTobe
on how to make sushi.
Can you believe that?
It's such a laugh trip.
I'm having so much fun.
Let's do it again tomorrow.
Let's look for a more difficult food,
and then let's watch her
make a fool of herself.
Game!
Think about it, Guimaras mangoes in Levante?
Do you think what you're doing is funny?
What do you care?
We're just having fun.
I already spoke to the doctor.
I told him it's better if I'll recover at home,
so don't worry, my child.
By tomorrow or the day after,
your father will be strong again.
Stronger than a horse or carabao.
That's good news, Father,
but don't force yourself.
Just take it easy.
You might go into a relapse
and have complications.
Don't worry, Florence,
I'll take care of your father.
I'll beat him up
if he skips his therapy and medicines.
It looks like it's more dangerous for me
to get beaten up than have a relapse.
How about you, Florence?
How are you doing there?
Both of you...
You and your mother decided
without consulting me.
Father, of course,
Mother and I don't want you to worry
especially since you
were about to undergo surgery.
Don't worry, Florence.
I already explained it to your father.
He's just being dramatic.
I understood your decision, my child.
You're sacrificing for me and our family,
but of course, I'm still concerned about you.
Well, are you doing okay there, Florence?
You don't have a problem?
Of course, Mother.
There's no problem.
I'm okay here.
I might get used to this
and decide to live here.
Oh, really?
Are you sure, Florence?
Remember, you made a promise to me
that the moment you get tired there,
you'll come home here.
Think of yourself.
Don't endure the pain.
Mother, I'm not suffering here.
Well, I admit that I'm having a hard time
because it's difficult to cook
for Don Ferell's grandsons,
but I've been warned before
that they are very picky eaters.
Kids are really like that, Florence.
If the kids refuse to eat
what you've cooked for them,
pinch them in the groin
or hit them a little on the head.
Hey, you're something else.
Look at the advice you're giving
to your daughter.
Don Ferell might get mad once he finds out
that she's hurting his grandsons.
But, Florence, this is what I want to know.
How are the people in the mansion?
Are rich families normal like us?
Or do they produce gold and magic?
They're just like us,
but there's a difference.
Actually, there's a big difference.
What do you mean?
Here in the world of rich people,
it's quieter and no one is talking.
When you're here,
you won't hear any noise or conversations.
No one is talking.
All of them have their own world.
Compared to our place,
we can hear everything.
The movement of the cats,
barking of the dogs,
and even the rat's rustle,
we can hear it, right?
If the silence in our place is deafening,
we can hear the gossip-mongers the whole day.
But here in the mansion,
the silence is deafening.
It seems like it's so lonely there.
What's the use of being rich
if you don't talk to each other?
If they're busy with their own worlds,
how would they know
what's inside their hearts?
I don't know, Father, but what I know is,
I'll never exchange our simple life
for this mansion.
Don't worry, Florence, you're already there.
That's right.
It's you who will bring noise,
fun, and light to that mansion.
I hope so, Mother and Father.
I hope I can share somehow
the happiness in our house
so the people here can be happy
and somehow feel joy.
I'll go ahead, Mother.
And Father, get well soon and take it easy,
so you won't have a relapse.
Good night.
I love you and I miss you.
Good night, my child.
I love you.
Do you think I'm scared of you?
I'm not scared of the Ferell brothers,
and I don't care no matter who you are.
Is that so?
Project eliminate Florence Dela Cruz
activated.
Let's go.
Hey, get your hands off me!
Ouch. What are you doing? Let me go!
Thank you, Owen.
Thank you for saving me
and choosing me over your brothers.
I'll always be here for you, Florence.
A new day, a new challenge.
Can you still take it, Florence?
Can you still cook for the naughty grandsons
of Grandpa Garp?
Or you will follow what you promised
to Mother and Father
and just go home?
Can you give me a sign?
Should I stay or should I go?
Hey you, I thought a ghost is scaring me,
but it's just you.
You frightened me.
Have you been here for a while?
I think you got lost.
Where did you come from?
Never ever give up, you can do it.
Hi.
Here it is.
So, how was it, Mr. Dencio?
You know,
this paella negra of yours is more delicious
if there's a vermouth.
Vermouth?
A Spanish wine.
As a matter of fact,
vermouth came from France and Italy,
but it became famous in Spain.
Shall I hit you with this?
Wait, how come you know a lot about food?
That's because, with all the food
the different chefs have cooked
and rejected by the Ferell brothers,
we somehow got used to sophisticated food.
That's true.
As for me,
my favorite is the classic French meal,
Coq au vin, a delicious chicken stew.
I remember that.
Of course, you can't outvote my favorite,
tomato bruschetta with balsamico
di moderna from the Italian cuisine.
- Excuse me?
- Yes?
It's not moderna, but modena.
Balsamico di modena, fettucine, linguine!
Lamborghini, Ferrari...
Confetti!
And you, don't feel bad
because you can cook delicious food.
Is that right? Right?
- Yes.
- Yes!
It just so happens that my wards
are picky eaters.
Don't worry, Florence, we're just here.
We're ready to eat the food
they refuse to eat.
But, Mr. Dencio, may I just ask,
why are the Ferells like that
when it comes to food?
I have no idea, Florence.
But from what I heard,
the late wife of Don Ferell, Dona Amanda,
was a very good cook.
That's true.
My father who used to work here
for a long time in the mansion
told me that.
And whenever Dona Amanda cooks,
it's like there's a feast.
They all want to be together.
Everyone is excited about
the food Dona Amanda cooked.
No, Dona Amanda is very talented.
According to Serafica...
Just by the scent,
Dona Amanda already knows
if her food is delicious or not.
Too bad their children didn't inherit
the talent of Dona Amanda
when it comes to cooking,
but they became busy with
their respective businesses of the Ferells.
That's why the grandsons
were left with Grandpa Garp.
What hurts the most is,
when Dona Amanda died,
it's like the system here
in the mansion changed.
Before, it was happy.
They ate together.
But now, it looks like they are on their own.
It's like they don't care about each other.
Florence, do you know the saying,
"the way to a man's heart
is through his stomach"?
Yes.
That saying is so worn out...
It's more worn out compared to the saying,
"love is blind".
Even if it's a worn-out saying,
there's still some truth to it.
And besides,
your mother and I won't be a couple
if not for this recipe.
Father, what are you cooking?
This is what you call, "a heart that loves".
Okay, send that over to the office.
Okay, Sir.
Grandpa Garp?
Can I talk to you?
Yes, you can.
I just want to ask why you hired me?
I just want to find out
why you got me as your cook.
I'm just a simple cook, I'm not a chef.
I'm just my mother's assistant
in her mobile eatery.
And I didn't also study
in any of the prestigious cooking schools.
And I don't have any work experience
in any of the sophisticated restaurants.
I have no capability to cook whatever
your grandsons would like to eat,
especially the dishes for the rich,
like international dishes.
What I can only do is home cooked dishes.
But despite that,
you still hired me as a cook here.
Why did you even hire me
despite my limitations?
I agree.
The first time I saw you, it made me think,
"Serafica is going crazy".
She's so desperate to hire someone like you.
I will be honest with you.
I didn't expect much,
knowing that when it comes to food,
my grandsons are so picky.
I didn't even expect that you'll stay long
in this household as a cook.
But when I tasted your dish, the balbacua,
I already told you, remember?
I remembered my wife's cooking...
What?
You stir the salad, get it from the bottom,
and the sauce should be on top.
- This is about to be cooked.
- No, not yet!
It smells good.
You can't taste this yet, it's still raw.
You're always hungry...
Come over here. No, that's off-limits!
Mix this.
Hey, what now?
Yes, that's correct,
and then put the carrots after that.
Not too much water, son. There, very good.
Hey, that's not yet cooked...
Out, out, out!
You, guys...
Here, you really want this?
Maybe I was hoping you can match my wife
when it comes to cooking.
Her cooking was so good
it bonded us as a family.
Every time we eat, we could feel that
we're a complete and happy family.
I was hoping that you can
make us a happy family again.
But you're right.
I was being unfair.
I expected too much of you.
I hired you for the wrong reason,
that's why, I'm apologizing to you.
Now if you're really having a hard time
and you can't do it,
I'll understand why you'd want to resign.
- What?
- And for all your troubles,
I'm willing to give you
a very good separation pay.
No... No, I won't resign, Grandpa Garp.
I can achieve your expectations of me.
What I can't do is match
how good your wife is,
when it comes to cooking.
We have different styles of cooking, right?
But I can help you become
a complete family again.
Or at the very least,
eat together like a family.
But...
But what?
But I need your help,
because I can't do this alone.
Okay, what will I do?
Hello.
Nanny, this is Aldus.
Yes, Aldus. Do you need anything?
Is she dead already?
Or did she quit?
Who?
Who else, but our cook?
Of course, not.
She's still here.
She's probably busy making your lunch.
Really?
But how come she hasn't asked
for my order yet?
Like I said, I want Italian for my lunch.
Are you sure?
She didn't ask you what you want for lunch?
Yes, Ma'am.
Actually, Florence is not yet here,
and I haven't seen her since breakfast.
So where is she?
All right.
What are you doing?
I'm preparing for lunch.
How come you only have one dish?
Didn't I tell you that
they each have their own food?
That is why you always have to cook them
their own unique meals
because they have
their respective food preferences.
What were you thinking, Florence?
What came into your mind
to disobey my orders?
I requested for this, Serafica.
Don Ferell.
Call the kids and tell them to join me
at the dining table.
Yes, Sir.
Right away, Sir.
This is nice.
Finally, we'll eat together.
I can't remember the last time this happened,
maybe because it's been a long time.
Either that or maybe I can't remember,
because I'm becoming senile.
Grandpa Garp, sorry to say this,
but I already told Ms. Serafica
that I prefer Italian for my lunch.
Actually, Grandpa, me too.
I also want chicken teriyaki.
Me too, Grandpa,
I'm craving for Chinese food.
I was planning to order because I heard
there's a newly opened
Cantonese style restaurant in the city.
This looks nice, Grandpa.
What did you prepare for us?
Florence calls this
the soup of the loving heart.
Cute! It's actually very witty, Grandpa,
because if you look very close,
you can see it's a tamarind broth
with banana blossoms.
It suits the name the loving heart.
Just because that dish has a cute name,
you expect us to eat that, Owen?
Honestly, I'm not in the mood
for another Filipino soup.
Not to disrespect,
but it doesn't look appetizing.
Does this have meat
or just full of banana hearts?
Please...
Let's give this a chance first.
Now if you really don't like it,
I will fire Florence.
But taste it first,
so you'd know if you'll like it or not.
Grandpa Gard is right.
As for me, it's okay,
and my life's motto anyway,
is I try everything at least once.
Okay, let's eat.
Go ahead and eat.
What's happening?
Tell me, Florence.
Why is this happening?
I thought of talking to Grandpa Garp.
Did you talk to Don Ferell
without asking my permission?
What's with you?
Are you compromising
my position in this family?
Let me explain Ms. Serafica.
I thought of a way
how I can do my job better as a cook here.
Go on.
I thought that
even if I watch videos from UTobe
the whole day
on how to cook Spanish, French,
or Italian dishes,
or whatever country that is,
I will not learn that.
That's why, I told Grandpa Garp
if he hired me
to cook whatever his grandsons like,
he made the wrong decision.
You said what?
That's the thing, Ms. Serafica.
I told him that what I can only cook
is what I've learned
from my parent's kitchen.
I can only cook the kinds of food
that I cook for my family.
If he doesn't want that,
I do not deserve to be the cook
for his grandsons.
So you took the initiative?
Well, next time inform me first
before you talk to Don Ferell.
Is that clear?
But I admire your courage.
Owen.
Florence?
Can we talk?
Sure.
You're awesome.
You're really good.
I'm impressed with you.
Wait, what's happening?
Everyone appreciated your cooking.
Really?
How?
Earlier, Grandpa Garp challenged us.
He said...
Taste it first.
Now if you really don't like it,
I will fire Florence.
And if anyone of us doesn't like your food,
we'll just tell him and he'll fire you.
- Decision?
- Exactly.
So am I fired already?
I'll go pack my things,
because it's impossible
that you all liked my cooking.
That's the thing
because all of us liked your cooking.
- It's impossible.
- Yes.
As in, everyone?
Yes.
As in, all of you?
Including Tristan?
Troy?
Aldus?
And even Nero?
Yes, including Nero.
- Wow.
- Not only that.
Grandpa decided that from now on,
you'll decide what we're going to eat.
Really?
Promise.
I'm happy that I met you.
I'm happy too,
that I'll always taste your loving heart.
It's you again?
You even woke me up.
Don't get tired of dreaming.
Grandpa Garp, I'm sorry.
I have a proposal for you.
You can still cook for us,
but now you have the option to study at GU,
if you want?
Can you balance work and study
at the same time?
Won't you have a hard time?
No, don't worry. I can handle that.
Me, of all people.
Owen?
Nero is okay with you.
You think he's just mad,
but he's okay with you.
As a matter of fact,
he's one of your biggest defenders
here in the mansion.
How did that happen?
Nero?
He's early.
Where is he going?
How are you doing?